Guide to the Frederick Albert Pottle Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Frederick Albert Pottle papers
1861-1979
1920-1979
MS 1605
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
10.25
The papers include correspondence, teaching materials, and writings that document Frederick Pottle's scholarly interest in English literature, primarily the work of James Boswell. The papers also reflect Pottle's involvement in the affairs of the Yale English Department, Colby College, and the Episcopal Church.
Pottle, Frederick A. (Frederick Albert), 1897-1987
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Christopher Pottle, 1991.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The correspondence, teaching materials, and writings in the Frederick Albert Pottle Papers focus primarily on Pottle's scholarly interests and to a lesser extent on his personal life. Although the earliest material dates from the nineteenth century, the papers are concentrated in the period of Pottle's teaching at Yale, ca. 1928-1970. Pottle's contributions to the study of James Boswell are evident throughout the papers, though his responsibilities as head of the Yale Editions of the Private Papers of James Boswell are not reflected in them.
The papers also document Pottle's involvement in several endeavors outside of Yale University. Pottle's religious commitment to the Episcopal Church is highlighted in the files for his work on the Joint Commission on Holy Matrimony, for the General Theological Seminary, and for his church and diocese. Pottle's devotion to his alma mater, Colby College, is evident in his files as a trustee and in the many speeches and lectures he gave there. Pottle's army service during World War I and his continuing involvement with the members of Evacuation Hospital #8 are reflected in his correspondence and writings.
The papers are organized in series by record format, but certain types of material can be found in more than one series. For instance, general correspondence with publishers is arranged in Series I, but correspondence concerning a particular title is in Series III.
Biographical / Historical
Frederick Albert Pottle, the foremost scholar of James Boswell, was born in Center Lowell, Maine, on August 3, 1897. He received his B.A. from Colby College in 1917, served in an Army evacuation hospital from 1917 to 1919, and then entered Yale University, earning his M.A. in 1921, and his Ph.D. in 1925. He became a full professor at Yale in 1930 and was named Sterling Professor of English in 1944. His work on Boswell commenced with his doctoral dissertation. After Yale acquired the rare Boswell manuscripts in 1949, Pottle became editor-in-chief of the Yale Editions of the Private Papers of James Boswell, serving in this capacity until 1979. Additionally, he wrote a multi-volume biography of Boswell. During his tenure at Yale, Pottle was chairman of the English Department and director of graduate studies. He also served as a trustee of Colby College and the General Theological Seminary. He married Marion Isobel Starbird, on September 9, 1920. They had three children, Annette who died young, Christopher and Samuel. Pottle died on May 16, 1987.
Arrangement
Arranged in four series: I: Correspondence, 1914-1978. II: Teaching Files, 1922-1966. III: Writing and Research Files, 1913-1979. IV: Personal Files, 1861-1974.
English literature -- Study and teaching; Marriage -- Religious aspects -- Episcopal Church; Boswell, James, 1740-1795; Pottle, Frederick A. (Frederick Albert), 1897-1987; Colby College; Yale University. Department of English
- Correspondence, 1914-1978; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  Pottle's correspondence is mainly with colleagues, students, publishers, professional societies, and religious groups. There is relatively little correspondence with Pottle family members and with Pottle's sister, Nellie Hankin, and her family. The files contain both incoming and outgoing correspondence.
  The bulk of the correspondence, which dates from the 1920s to the 1970s, is arranged alphabetically by individual or corporate name. When there are few letters from a single correspondent, these have been grouped with others having the same initial letter. Following Pottle's own arrangement, correspondence for the years 1971-1979 is filed by year. There is some overlap between the alphabetical and chronological files for the early 1970s.
  - Alphabetical file
    - A, 1923-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - Academy of American Poets, 1961-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - American Council of Learned Societies, 1939-1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - American Expeditionary Force. Evacuation Hospital # 8, 1947-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5-9)
    - American Philosophical Society
      - General, 1940-1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Lewis Prize, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Ba-Be, 1927-1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bi-Bu, 1936-1968 (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
    - Barrell, Joseph, 1952-1971 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Batty, W. R., 1929-1959 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Becker, Robert A., 1958 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Brady, Frank, 1961-1971 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Brogan, Howard O., 1964-1969 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - C, 1929-1972 (Box 2, Folder 20-22)
    - Cameron, John A., 1962-1975 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Chapman, R. W., 1930-1950 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Cherniak, Judith, 1960-1972 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Christ Church, New Haven, 1927-1971 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Church Club of New York, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Colby College, 1919-1972 (Box 3, Folder 28-29)
    - Cornell University Press, 1941-1971 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - D, 1922-1970 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Davidson, Herbert Marc, 1919-1924 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Drake, Robert Y., 1955-1972 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Duprée, Philip, 1914-1922 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - E, 1932-1971 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Elizabethan Club, 1955-1971 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Encyclopedia Americana, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Episcopal Church. Joint Commission on Holy Matrimony
      - 1940 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      - 1941-1947 (Box 4, Folder 39-42)
    - Episcopal Church at Yale, 1954-1965 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - F, 1922-1968 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Fletcher, Edward G., 1922-1926 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Fogle, Richard Harter, 1948-1968 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Funk and Wagnalls Company, 1947-1959 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Ga-Ge, 1919-1971 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Gi-Gu, 1941-1971 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Gammack, John Wilson, 1930-1936 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - General Theological Seminary, 1955-1967 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - H, 1938-1971 (Box 5, Folder 52-55)
    - Hall, Bertram E., 1929-1932 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Hankin family, 1961-1972 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Hanson, Adolph M., 1942-1955 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - I, 1944-1967 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Indiana University, 1959-1966 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Indiana University Press, 1961-1963 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - J, 1931-1973 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1945-1971 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Johnstone, Rutherford T., 1921-1927 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - K, 1929-1971 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - Kadambi, Shantha, 1957-1970 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Keats and Shelley Journal, 1956-1966 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - Knight, Archie T., 1917-1924 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - L, 1928-1972 (Box 6, Folder 69-70)
    - Leonard, Neil, 1945-1968 (Box 6, Folder 71)
    - Lewis, Wilmarth S., 1933-1971 (Box 6, Folder 72)
    - Lichtenstein family, 1920-1942 (Box 6, Folder 73)
    - Low, Janet K., 1957-1967 (Box 6, Folder 74)
    - Lustig, Irma, 1966-1971 (Box 6, Folder 75)
    - M, 1924-1971 (Box 7, Folder 76-79)
    - MacCarthy, Gerald R., 1917-1925 (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - McFarland, Thomas, 1957-1969 (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1955-1971 (Box 7, Folder 82)
    - Modern Language Association, 1947-1969 (Box 7, Folder 83)
    - N, 1931-1971 (Box 7, Folder 84)
    - O, 1931-1970 (Box 8, Folder 85)
    - Ober, William B., 1945-1970 (Box 8, Folder 86)
    - P, 1922-1970 (Box 8, Folder 87-88)
    - Perkins, Perley, 1924-1928 (Box 8, Folder 89)
    - Pottle family, 1925-1965 (Box 8, Folder 90)
    - Q, 1960-1967 (Box 8, Folder 91)
    - R, 1922-1971 (Box 8, Folder 92-93)
    - Ridenhour, George W., 1965-1969 (Box 8, Folder 94)
    - S, 1928-1971 (Box 9, Folder 95-98)
    - Sheldon, Noble W., 1919-1924 (Box 9, Folder 99)
    - Simpson, Lydia P., 1932-1960 (Box 9, Folder 100)
    - Stonehill, Charles A., 1922-1935 (Box 9, Folder 101)
    - Swift, F. K., 1949-1964 (Box 9, Folder 102)
    - T, 1925-1972 (Box 9, Folder 103-104)
    - U, 1925-1969 (Box 9, Folder 105)
    - University of Illinois, 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 106)
    - V, 1934-1967 (Box 9, Folder 107)
    - Viking Press, Inc., 1955-1965 (Box 9, Folder 108)
    - W, 1922-1972 (Box 10, Folder 109-111)
    - Walsh, Joseph L, 1923-1966 (Box 10, Folder 112)
    - Warnock, Robert, 1948-1966 (Box 10, Folder 113)
    - Y, Z, 1932-1971 (Box 10, Folder 114)
    - Yale University
      - General, 1933-1972 (Box 10, Folder 115-116)
      - Committee to Advise the President on the Appointment of a Director for the Beinecke Library, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 117)
      - Davenport College, 1952-1971 (Box 10, Folder 118)
      - English Department Committee on a Major Appointment, 1946-1948 (Box 10, Folder 119)
      - Graduate School, 1956-1967 (Box 10, Folder 120)
    - Yale University Press, 1929-1972 (Box 10, Folder 121)
    - Unidentified, 1929-1976 (Box 10, Folder 122)
  - Chronological file
    - 1972 (Box 11, Folder 123-125)
    - 1973 (Box 11, Folder 126-128)
    - 1974 (Box 11, Folder 129-130)
    - 1975 (Box 11, Folder 131-132)
    - 1976 (Box 12, Folder 133-135)
    - 1977 (Box 12, Folder 136-137)
- Teaching Files, 1922-1966; Series II
  This series contains lectures, notes, assignments, bibliographies, and examinations for courses Pottle taught at Yale. There is also one folder of similar materials associated with Pottle's teaching at New Hampshire State College. The lectures included in this series were in Pottle's files of course related materials. The material is arranged, as Pottle filed it, by course numbers. The university changed these course designations over the years, the titles of the courses were rewritten, and the same course number can have two different titles. For example, The Age of Wordsworth was also given as The Romantic Poets, but not always with the same course number. Pottle taught this course over many years and it contains the are the largest number of folders in the series. Since specialized courses often contained some of the same subjects taught in a more general course, occasionally, there are lectures filed with one course though the lecture originated in another course. At the end of this series, there are some course- related materials without a clear indication of the particular course with which they were associated.
  - New Hampshire State College, 1922 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Yale University
    - English 20, 1938-1941 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - English 25, 1948, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - English 30, History of English Language, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - English 34/35/144, Age of Johnson, 1937-1951, undated (Box 14, Folder 5-12)
    - English 48/150, English Poets of the Nineteenth Century, 1948-1962, undated (Box 14, Folder 13-19)
    - English 61/160, Theories of Poetry, 1925-1939, undated (Box 15, Folder 20-21)
    - English 101, Old English, 1928-1951, undated (Box 15, Folder 22-26)
    - English 112, Chaucer, 1924-1925 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - English 136, Boswell Papers, undated (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - English142, The Romantic Movement, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - English 144, 1947-1951 (Box 16, Folder 30-31)
    - English 146, 1951-1966 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - English 150, The Romantic Movement/The Age of Wordsworth, 1931-1963, undated (Box 16, Folder 33-44)
    - English 150, The Romantic Movement/The Age of Wordsworth, 1931-1963, undated (Box 17, Folder 45-51)
    - English 152, Keats and Shelley, 1948-1955 (Box 17, Folder 52-53)
  - Miscellaneous course materials
    - Judas lecture [notes], 1943 (Box 17, Folder 54)
    - Romantic movement figures [lectures], [1951?] (Box 17, Folder 55)
    - Graduate student exam questions, 1951-1961 (Box 17, Folder 56)
    - Bibliographical lectures, undated (Box 17, Folder 57)
    - Boswell [notes], undated (Box 17, Folder 58)
    - Chesterfield and Johnson [lecture], undated (Box 17, Folder 59)
    - Johnson and Boswell [lecture], undated (Box 17, Folder 60)
    - Johnson's poetry [lecture], undated (Box 17, Folder 61)
    - Teaching Old French, undated (Box 17, Folder 62)
    - Walpole [lecture], undated (Box 17, Folder 63)
- Writing and Research Files, 1913-1979; Series III
  This series includes articles, lectures, book reviews, introductions, short stories, and poems written by Pottle, as well as background research files. The writings are arranged in chronological order. Writings lacking dates are arranged alphabetically by title after the dated material. A partial bibliography of Pottle's writings is available in Series IV. The file for an individual title may contain correspondence, notes, reviews, and drafts for unpublished works. Reprints for published papers are generally not included. The articles and lectures relate to literary topics and also to religious subjects. Many of Pottle's talks at Davenport College, Yale University, and also at Christ Church, New Haven, are documented here, as is the book, Stretchers, which records Pottle's World War I experience. The series concludes with one folder of book reviews by Pottle and background files containing research notes and correspondence arranged by topic.
  - Prose manuscripts, [191-] (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Address at commencement, 1913 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - "The Bug Jar", 1917 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Poems, 1917-1918 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - "Boswell's Ballad The Grocer of London ", [192-] (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - "Boswell and the Jacobite Lady", [192-] (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - "The Influence of Shelley on Browning as shown in Pauline and Parcelsus " [master's thesis], 1921 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - "A Theory of Poetry", 1921 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - "The Art of Mme. de Lafayette" [essay submitted for the John Addison Porter Prize], 1921 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Shelley and Browning, 1923 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Stretchers, 1924-1938 (Box 18, Folder 11-13)
  - "Chaucer and the Romance of the Rose", [1925?] (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - " All Cruels Else Subscribed -- A Note on King Lear, III, vii, 64", 1925 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - "Boswell and Corsica", [1926?] (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - "St. Bartholomew the Great", 1926 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - "Letter LI of [Goldsmith's] Citizen of the World Papers ", 1929 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - "James Boswell: Spanish Cavalier", 1929 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Contemporary English drama [lecture], 1929 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - The Literary Career of James Boswell, Esq., 1929-1930 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Modern Language Association [Cleveland meeting lecture], 1929-1930 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Private Papers of James Boswell from Malahide Castle, 1929-1932 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Chapel addresses and sermons, 1930-1955 (Box 19, Folder 24-25)
  - "Glen Cove Series", 1931 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - "Why I Am a Catholic", 1932 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - "The Virtues and Limitations of the Historical Attitude in the Teaching of English" [Northeast Association of Teachers of English], 1933 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Good Friday address [Colby College], 1933 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - "A Somewhat Lugubrious Note to the Happy Purchaser" [Isham's sale catalogue], 1933 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - "Literature" [Northeast School Superintendents meeting], 1933 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Boswell and the Girl from Botany Bay, 1933-1938 (Box 19, Folder 32-33)
  - "The New Critics and the Historical Method", 1933, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - "Reading of Sophocles' Oedipus Tyrannus " [Davenport College], 1935 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - "Lux in Tenebris" [Berkeley Divinity School], 1935 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Yale Library Associates, 1935 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Journal of a Tour of the Hebrides [reviews, notices], 1936 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Index to the Private Papers of James Boswell, 1937 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - "Relation of Science to Drama" and "Poetry and Drama" [Dwight Hall, Yale University], 1937 (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Davenport College lectures on Yeats, 1938 (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Davenport College lecture on MacLeish, 1938 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - "Boswell in London" [Bucknell University], 1938 (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Colby Library Associates [lectures], 1938, 1949, 1951, undated (Box 20, Folder 44)
  - Wordsworth's ode: Intimations of Immortality [English Institute], 1941 (Box 20, Folder 45)
  - "Emergent Criticism" [Messenger lectures, Cornell University], 1941 (Box 20, Folder 46)
  - Idiom of Poetry, 1941-1950 (Box 20, Folder 47)
  - Presentations of honorary degree recipients [Yale commencements], 1942-1943 (Box 20, Folder 48)
  - "William Lyon Phelps, 1865-1943" (Box 20, Folder 49)
  - Modern Language Association [lecture], 1944 (Box 20, Folder 50)
  - "The Historical Approach to Problems of Usage in English Pronunciation" [New Haven State Teachers College], 1944 (Box 20, Folder 51)
  - "Literature and Religion" [Davenport College], 1945 (Box 20, Folder 52)
  - Catharsis, 1945-1946 (Box 20, Folder 53)
  - "The Intensive Program on Modern Languages at Yale" [University of Kansas], 1946 (Box 20, Folder 54)
  - Wordsworth and Freud or The Theology of the Unconscious [commencement, General Theological Seminary], 1948 (Box 20, Folder 55)
  - Sesquicentennial address [Lovell, Maine], 1948 (Box 20, Folder 56)
  - " Cum laude " [Exeter Academy], 1949, 1951 (Box 20, Folder 57)
  - "Address on Boswell" [Modern Language Association], 1950 (Box 20, Folder 58)
  - "Literature and Religion" [Bucknell University], 1951 (Box 20, Folder 59)
  - "Properer for a Sermon: Coleridge's Theory and Practice" [Wellesley College], 1951 (Box 20, Folder 60)
  - "The Case of Shelley" [correspondence re original article and reprint in Oxford Press anthology], 1951-1952, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 61-62)
  - "Boswell Revalued" [lecture, several campuses], 1951-1955 (Box 20, Folder 63)
  - "The New Criticism: Its Virtues and Defects" [lectures, Oberlin College], 1954 (Box 20, Folder 64)
  - Vassar College [lecture], 1954 (Box 20, Folder 65)
  - Letters to the editor [various], 1955-1956 (Box 20, Folder 66)
  - Tributes [Colby College addresses], 1956, 1958, undated (Box 20, Folder 67)
  - McGraw Hill talk on Boswell, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 68)
  - Article for Yale Lit, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 69)
  - "English Literature" [Davenport College], 1962 (Box 20, Folder 70)
  - "Boswell as Icarus" [notes on the Arcadian year], 1963 (Box 20, Folder 71)
  - Ponceau's First Leaveand "Réchoussat's Christmas" [readings at Davenport College], [1964?] (Box 20, Folder 72)
  - "Notes for a Theory of Literary History", 1964 (Box 21, Folder 73)
  - "The Role of Asia in the Dramatic Action of Shelley's Prometheus Unbound ", 1965 (Box 21, Folder 74)
  - Lectures [Colby College], 1965 (Box 21, Folder 75)
  - James Boswell, The Earlier Years, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 76-77)
  - "Current Developments in the Teaching of English Literature at Yale", 1966 (Box 21, Folder 78)
  - "The Sweet Miracle" [Davenport College], 1966 (Box 21, Folder 79)
  - "The Part Played by Horace Walpole and James Boswell in the General Quarrel between Rousseau and Hume: A Reconsideration" [from Walpole Essays in The Yale Edition of Horace Walpole's Correspondence ], 1967 (Box 21, Folder 80-81)
  - "Collecting" [York University, Toronto], 1967 (Box 21, Folder 82)
  - "A Literary Critic's Approach" [Lake Mahopac], [1968?] (Box 21, Folder 83)
  - "The Writing of a Biography: Boswell's Earlier Years" [University of Oregon], 1968 (Box 21, Folder 84)
  - "Can Straightforward Chronology Be Employed as a Structuring Principle in Literary Biography of the Present Day?" [Modern Language Association], 1968 (Box 21, Folder 85)
  - "Boswell as Biographer and Biographee" [University of Illinois], 1969 (Box 21, Folder 86)
  - "William Lyon Phelps", 1969 (Box 21, Folder 87-88)
  - "Creed Not Annulled", [1970?] (Box 21, Folder 89)
  - "To the Class of '76, Davenport College", 1972 (Box 21, Folder 90)
  - "Synchrony and Diachrony" [for Wimsatt festschrift], 1973 (Box 21, Folder 91)
  - "Robert Strider", 1974 (Box 21, Folder 92)
  - "Cleanth Brooks" [Davenport College], 1975 (Box 21, Folder 93)
  - "Report on Literacy and the Reading Public in the 18th Century ", 1975 (Box 21, Folder 94)
  - "An Account of Goldsmith's Last Illness with an Investigation into the Cause of His Death", undated (Box 21, Folder 95)
  - "The Adventures of Ebenezer Titmarsh", undated (Box 21, Folder 96)
  - Alfred de Musset poems [translations], undated (Box 21, Folder 97)
  - "Another Way of Love", undated (Box 21, Folder 98)
  - "Boswell and the Douglas Cause", undated (Box 21, Folder 99)
  - "Boswell as Journalist" [Modern Language Association], undated (Box 21, Folder 100)
  - Boswell lecture [Northwestern University, South Carolina], undated (Box 21, Folder 101)
  - "Boswell's Johnson and Pottle's Boswell" [Adelphi College], undated (Box 22, Folder 102)
  - "Chauncey Brewster Tinker", undated (Box 22, Folder 103)
  - "Cleanth Brooks" [introduction], undated (Box 22, Folder 104)
  - Colby College [lectures], undated (Box 22, Folder 105)
  - "David, a Sentimental Ghost Story", undated (Box 22, Folder 106)
  - Dodsley talk on Ogham, undated (Box 22, Folder 107)
  - "The Douglas Case: Judas", undated (Box 22, Folder 108)
  - "Dramatic Interpretation", undated (Box 22, Folder 109)
  - Emerson's verse, undated (Box 22, Folder 110)
  - "An Epistle to Tristram Shandy", undated (Box 22, Folder 111)
  - "Fielding's Theory of Comedy", undated (Box 22, Folder 112)
  - "The Four Zoas", undated (Box 22, Folder 113)
  - General Theological Seminary [lecture], undated (Box 22, Folder 114)
  - "Gold Beads", undated (Box 22, Folder 115)
  - "The History of Juilly Seine et Marne", undated (Box 22, Folder 116)
  - "How to Become a Wordsworthian and Like It", undated (Box 22, Folder 117)
  - Introductions [Kokeritz, Lattimore, MacLeish, Phelps, Prouty, Reed, Ringler], undated (Box 22, Folder 118)
  - "James Boswell, Journalist, A Study in Ontogeny", undated (Box 22, Folder 119)
  - " The Land of Heart's Desire by W. B. Yeats" [adaptation], undated (Box 22, Folder 120)
  - Lee Academy address, undated (Box 22, Folder 121)
  - "Literary Biography", undated (Box 22, Folder 122)
  - "Loyalties", undated (Box 22, Folder 123)
  - Maine Club, New Haven [lecture], undated (Box 22, Folder 124)
  - "The Making of the Life of Johnson ", undated (Box 22, Folder 125)
  - "The Meaning of Shelley's Glirastes ", undated (Box 22, Folder 126)
  - "New Catharsis" [Kent School, New London], undated (Box 22, Folder 127)
  - "On the Reliability of Eighteenth Century Newspapers", undated (Box 22, Folder 128)
  - "Percy Bysshe Shelley", undated (Box 22, Folder 129)
  - Poems, undated (Box 22, Folder 130)
  - "Problems in editing Boswell's Journal " [New York Sun], undated (Box 22, Folder 131)
  - "Reading in the Army" [Colby College], undated (Box 22, Folder 132)
  - "Readings in Old English" [Berkeley Divinity School], undated (Box 22, Folder 133)
  - "The Role of Asia in the Dramatic Action of Shelley's Prometheus Unbound ", undated (Box 22, Folder 134)
  - "Shelley's Ode to the West Wind ", undated (Box 22, Folder 135)
  - "The Strange Story of the Chevalier D'Eon", undated (Box 22, Folder 136)
  - "Suggestions for Better Programing in the Teaching of English Literature" [lectures, South Carolina, Oberlin, Richmond], undated (Box 22, Folder 137)
  - Thomas Barnard [Guild of Scholars], undated (Box 22, Folder 138)